Hello.
We are now ready to set up our mushrooms range projectile attack to get started.
If you head over to the mushroom blueprint folder, just right click and go.
Blueprint class, select an actor and just call this projectile.
Underscore BP.
If we open it up.
We will go to components and go ahead and look for paper flipbook.
With the paper Philip book selected under for the book Look for the Mushroom project that we just made,
and I think it's kind of small.
So with the anchor checked.
Increase its size to something like five.
Then I want you to go ahead and look for sphere collision.
Now this collision will represent the collision that all projectiles are going to have.
Just move it.
So it kind of fits around your flipbook and we can adjust it sphere radius here.
I'm to make it a bit smaller so it just fits around my flipbook.
If you want more precise movement when you're moving around an object, what we can do is go here under
set position, grid, snap value.
And if I'm making something like one, I'm going to have much more precise movement when I move my sphere.
Okay, So next we need to be able to make sure that our projectile can move.
So if we go to add and look for projectile movement.
This will make it to our project.
I can move here under projectile and initial and max speed.
We can control the speed that our projectile will move.
If I put a value of something like 500 here and a value of 1000 here, it will mean my projectile will
start with an initial speed of 500 and then it will work its way up to a speed of 1000.
So you can do that in your project to increase gradually over time.
But I want my projectile to always be the same speed.
So under both of these values and we'll have a value of 1000.
If we click the simulation button, it's going to simulate how a projectile is going to move.
Right now, it kind of falls to the ground, and that is because by default, our projectile is affected
by gravity.
I don't want mine to be affected by gravity.
So if I just let my projectile movement and go over to the details, if I look for gravity under projectile
gravity scale, I'm going to change this to P zero.
And that will mean my projectile will not be affected by gravity.
Now, if I go back to my paperclip.
So let me just find it.
Okay, so I found it.
If I just clicked simulate my projectile should now just move in a straight line.
Most.
Okay.
So the next thing we need to do is make it so that whenever this project overlaps or play a character,
it will damage them.
So if we set the sphere and scroll down and go to on component, we can overlap.
When something overlaps their sphere, we're going to check to see if it was equal to the player character.
So a track of other actor and more equal.
And then I'm going to right click and I get player character.
If this is true, it's almost like a branch.
Then I'm going to get my PAC actor.
I'm going to fly down a storm.
Then I'm going to get my flipbook.
And we're going to set the flipbook animation to be the projectile being destroyed.
So this one mushroom projectile explode.
We then going to get our paper flip book again and get the flip book left.
This will get how long the animation is.
And after we get how long the animation is, we're going to destroy our flipbook.
So I just drag up here and look for destroy actor.
So when our player actor overlaps, it's there.
We apply one damage to them.
So I've got to put down chair.
So on the base damage, but one then went off to change to the mushroom explode flipbook.
We'll get how long the flip occurs.
After it's finished playing, we'll then destroy this actor.
So if I just go compile and close this, the next thing we're going to do is make it run.
Our player character gets within a certain radius of our enemy.
It will start shooting projectiles.